Conor Driscoll

Web Developer and Technologist with a front-end focus



Hello.

I'm an experienced web developer, and technologist in Richmond, Virginia. My goal is to contribute work on compelling projects that have a positive and lasting impact. While my focus is on front-end development, I strive to be a generalist who grasps the entire scope of successful website and web application systems.

Education

Academy of Art University

'12 Masters Program New Media Design

Saint Joseph's University

'03 Bachelor's of Science Psychology

Contact

driscoll66.com

conor@driscoll66.com

804.929.5203

Experience

Senior Web Developer

COLAB Digital Agency - Richmond, Virginia - March 2019 - December 2022

- Developed multiple web applications, themes, templates, and plugins for a variety of platforms and CMS (e.g. WordPress, Drupal, Kentico)
- Codeveloped the COLAB Baseline WordPress theme. (LumberJack MVC framework, Twig templates, Laravel Mix, TwentyTwentyOne styling)
- Led our team in multiple knowledge-base fronts: front-end technologies, Vue and Javascript, modern JS practices, technical search engine optimization, performance metrics, and ADA compliance.
- Worked with our strategy and design teams to expand institutional knowledge, and focus our work on user-centric web principles.

Lead WordPress Developer

Spotzer Digital Media - Amsterdam, Netherlands - January 2016 - March 2018

- Designed and developed WordPress product that has grown into one of Spotzer's successful products.
- Continual growth with a minimal team, while our product and reach had expanded to multiple international markets.
- Worked on hundreds of sites, and campaigns for countless small and medium businesses.
- Our team's most sought-after problem solvers, dealing with a multitude of issues that arise from digital marketing.

Designer/Developer & Digital Media Lead Dollamur LP - Campbell, California - May 2012 - May 2015

- Developed Dollamur.com a high powered eCommerce platform built in Magento and integrated with Dynamics ERP
- Optimized organic marketing strategies to rank first in sixteen of our top twenty keywords. Oversaw Google Adwords, Analytics, and Search Console, as well as, online press releases, news and social media accounts, created graphics, ad materials for numerous nationwide campaigns.

Skills

Front End Development, JavaScript, TypeScript, Vue, React - Enterprise Level WordPress, Drupal, Laravel, PHP - Digital Marketing, SEO, performance metrics, ADA Compliance, User-centric best practices, Adobe Creative Suite.